Guide to the Human Service Employees Registration and Voter Education Fund (Human SERVE) records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Human Service Employees Registration and Voter Education Fund (Human SERVE) Records,
1982-2000
Human Service Employees Registration and Voter Education Fund (Human SERVE)
63 linear feet (70,500 items in 47 record storage boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library. New York, NY.
5018097
History
The Human Service Employees Registration and Voter Education Fund (Human SERVE) was formed as a nonprofit organization in 1983 by Richard A. Cloward and Frances Fox Piven. It played a catalytic role in the passage of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (Cloward and Piven stood behind President Clinton at the bill signing on May 20, 1993). The Act requires states to permit people to register to vote when they get or renew drivers licenses or when they apply for benefits in welfare (Food Stamps, Medicaid, Women Infants and Children offices, and disability agencies). The Act went into effect in January 1995 and Human SERVE played a leading role in the effort to improve implementation by state officials especially in social service agencies. Human SERVE closed its doors in June 2000 having reached its goal of changing the American voter registration system by opening up access to people at the bottom of the socioeconomic scale.
Scope and Content
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 34 series:
Series I: Human Serve Launching
Series II: Early Campaigns
Series III: Human Serve Publications
Series IV: Proposals
Series V: Foundations
Series VI: Fundraising
Series VII: Funders
Series VIII: Nonprofit Agencies: 1985-1988
Series IX: Nonprofit Agencies: 1995-1996
Series X: National Organizations
Series XI: Labor
Series XII: States
Series XIII: New York State Executive Orders
Series XIV: New York State Legislation
Series XV: New York State Implementation
Series XVI: New York State Subjects
Series XVII: New York City Early Years
Series XVIII: New York City Voter Assistance Ccommission
Series XIX: New York City NVRA Implementation
Series XX: New York City Nonprofits
Series XXI: New York City Subjects
Series XXII: New York Legal
Series XXIII: Pre-NVRA State by State
Series XXIV: D.C. Office
Series XXV: Federal Legislation
Series XXVI: Federal Agencies
Series XXVII: NVRA Implementation
Series XXVIII: Legal Restraints
Series XXIX: Press
Series XXX: Voter Registration and Turnout Data
Series XXXI: Subjects
Series XXXII: Chronologies (Staff Correspondence Files)
Series XXXIII: Board/Staff
Series XXXIV: Internal Administration/Operations
Subjects
Human Service Employees Registration and Voter Education Fund.; Cloward, Richard A.; Piven, Frances Fox.; Cloward, Richard A.; Piven, Frances Fox.; Voter registration.; Manuscripts; Letters
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
Gift of Human SERVE 2000
- Series I: Human Serve Launching
  - Announcing Strategy (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Campaign, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Campaign, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Campaign, [n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Initial Outreach Questionnaire (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Campaign: Support from other organizations, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Campaign: Support from other organizations, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Report on New York Voter Registration Campaign (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - National School of Social Work Campaign, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Songs for Organizers, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - New Registrant Numbers and Agencies, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II: Early Campaigns
  - Emergency Campaign to Save Human Services- Protests, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Freedom Summer, 1984 #1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Freedom Summer, 1984 #2 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - October 4, 1984 #1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - October 4, 1984 #2 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series III: Human Serve Publications
  - Descriptions (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Reports/Papers/Analyses, 1983-1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Reports/Papers/Analyses, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Kits (1) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Kits (2) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Brochures and Leaflets (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Newsletters (General) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Motor Voter Booklet Preparation Arizona, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Motor Voter Booklet Preparation, Colorado, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Motor Voter Booklet Preparation Edits, June 1986- August 3, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Motor Voter Booklet Preparation Edits, August 6, 1986- October 1986 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Motor Voter Booklet Preparation Graphs, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Motor Voter Booklet Preparation Interviews, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Motor Voter Booklet Preparation Letters, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Motor Voter Booklet Preparation, Michigan, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Motor Voter Booklet Preparation Notes, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Motor Voter Booklet Preparation Questionnaire, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Motor Voter Booklet Preparation Research, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Motor Voter Booklet Preparation State Info, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Motor Voter Booklet, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Executive Orders (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Update/National Survey, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - News on Agency Based Voter Registration, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - News on Agency Based Voter Registration, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Investing in Democracy High Schools Program, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Implementation Manual Preparation (1) (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Implementation Manual Preparation (2) (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - NVRA Implementation Manual (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Website (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Series IV: Proposals
  - 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Progress Reports, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Progress Reports, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Progress Reports, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - National Center for Policy Alternatives Joint Proposal, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - New Jersey, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - 1986 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - 1987 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Washington D.C. Advocacy, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Progress Reports, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - 1988 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Progress Reports, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Minority Empowerment, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Legal, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - 1989 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Progress Reports, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Women's Health Empowerment, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Public Schools, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Progress Reports, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Progress Reports, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - New York, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - New York, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Progress Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Progress Reports, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Disability Empowerment, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Progress Reports, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Progress Reports, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Progress Reports, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Progress Reports, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Progress Reports, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Women Empowerment, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - New York Proposals, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Progress Reports, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Progress Reports, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Progress Reports, 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 82)
- Series V: Foundations
  - Legal Guidance for Funding Voter Registration (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Rejections (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - rEJECTIONS, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Letters, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Prospects (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Abelard (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Amalgamated Bank of New York (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - American Can Company (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Arkay (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Association of Community Organization for Reform Now (ACORN) (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - A Territory Resource (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Babcock (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Beldon (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Best Products (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Boehm (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Borg-Warner (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Bydale (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Campaign For Human Development (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Campbell Soup Fund (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Center for Community Change (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Citizens Participation Project (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Citizens Vote, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Communications Workers of America (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Community Service Society (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Cottonwood (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Cudahy (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Nathan Cummings (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Cummins Engine (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Dayton-Hudson (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Democratic National Committee (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Aaron Diamond (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Discount (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Episcopal City Mission (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Field (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Ford, 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Ford, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Ford, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Ford, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Ford, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Forum Institute (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Fund for a Democratic Majority (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Fund for the City of New York (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Funder's Committee for Voter Registration and Education (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Funding Exchange/National Committee Funds (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - EMSA Fund (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - General Mills (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Harris (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Heinz (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Hunt Alternatives (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - James Earl Chaney (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Jewish Communal (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Joint Foundation Support (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Joyce, 1985-1991 (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Joyce, 1992-1999 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - J.M. Kaplan (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - Kennilworth (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - League of Women Voters (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Levinson (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - J. Roderick MacArthur (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Company (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Charles Stewart Mott (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - National Association of Community Health Centers (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - National United Service Agencies (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - Needmor (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - New Land (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - New Prospect (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - New World (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - New York (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - New York City Voter Assist Commission (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - New York Community Trust (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Nokomis (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - Norman (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - North Shore Unitarian Universalist Veatch Program (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - North Star Fund (Box 5, Folder 159)
  - Open Society Institute (Box 5, Folder 160)
  - Ottinger (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - Otto Bremer (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - Paralyzed Veterans of America (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - Planned Parenthood Association (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - Playboy (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - Presbyterian Church (Box 5, Folder 166)
  - Prudential (Box 5, Folder 167)
  - Public Concern (Box 5, Folder 168)
  - Public Welfare (Box 5, Folder 169)
  - Reed (Box 5, Folder 170)
  - Charles H. Revson (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - Riverside Church Benevolence (Box 5, Folder 172)
  - Rockefeller (Box 5, Folder 173)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - Rockefeller Family Associates (Box 5, Folder 175)
  - Rockefeller Family Fund (Box 5, Folder 176)
  - Laurance S. Rockefeller Trust (Box 5, Folder 177)
  - Samuel Rubin (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - Scherman (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - Schumann (Box 5, Folder 180)
  - Sidney Stern Memorial Trust (Box 5, Folder 181)
  - L.J. Skaggs and Mary C. Skaggs (Box 5, Folder 182)
  - Snyder (Box 5, Folder 183)
  - Software Publishing Corporation (Box 5, Folder 184)
  - Sophia Fund (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - Stern Fund (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - Streisand (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - Sunflower (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - Taconic (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - Threshold (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - Tides (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - Travelers (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - Trull (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - United Methodist of Global Ministries (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - United Way (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - USA Votes (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - Vanguard Public (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - Villers (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Vote Now '96 (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Albert and Bessie Warner Fund (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Windom Fund (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - Working Assets (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - Yale Public Interest Law (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - Youth Project (Box 5, Folder 204)
- Series VI: Fundraising
  - General (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - California (Box 5, Folder 206)
  - Chicago, Illinois (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - Old Legal (Box 5, Folder 208)
  - Massachusetts (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - New Jersey (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - New York (Box 5, Folder 211)
  - Resource Development (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - Strategies (Box 5, Folder 213)
  - Texas (Box 5, Folder 214)
- Series VII: Funders
  - Possible, 1984-1996 (Box 5, Folder 215)
  - Possible, 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - Letters To, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 217)
  - Individual, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - Individual, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 219)
  - Letters To, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 220)
  - Letters To, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 221)
  - Individual, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 222)
  - Letters To, January 1989-August 1989 (Box 6, Folder 223)
  - Letters To: Legal, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 224)
  - Letters To, September 1989-October 1989 (Box 6, Folder 225)
  - Letters To, 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 226)
  - Letters To, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 227)
  - Letters To, 1991-1996 (Box 6, Folder 228)
  - Letters To, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 229)
  - Roger Alcaly (Box 6, Folder 230)
  - Mark Alcott (Box 6, Folder 231)
  - Franz Allina (Box 6, Folder 232)
  - Anonymous (Box 6, Folder 233)
  - Ed Asner (Box 6, Folder 234)
  - Patricia Bauman (Box 6, Folder 235)
  - Charles Benton (Box 6, Folder 236)
  - Blair Clark (Box 6, Folder 237)
  - David Clennon (Box 6, Folder 238)
  - Richard Cloward & Frances Fox Piven (Box 6, Folder 239)
  - Dave Dellinger (Box 6, Folder 240)
  - Adelaide DeMenil (Box 6, Folder 241)
  - Richard Dennis (Box 6, Folder 242)
  - Dreyfuss (Box 6, Folder 243)
  - Carol Ferry (Box 6, Folder 244)
  - Frederick W. Field (Box 6, Folder 245)
  - Ronald Goldsand (Box 6, Folder 246)
  - Richard Grand-Jean & Chris Doudna (Box 6, Folder 247)
  - Jay Harris (Box 6, Folder 248)
  - Anne Hartwell (Box 6, Folder 249)
  - John Heimerdinger (Box 6, Folder 250)
  - John Henry (Box 6, Folder 251)
  - Jay Hershenson (Box 6, Folder 252)
  - John Hunting (Box 6, Folder 253)
  - George Katz (Box 6, Folder 254)
  - Dr. John Marks & Martha Marks (Box 6, Folder 255)
  - Stephen B. Martin (Box 6, Folder 256)
  - Anne Martindell (Box 6, Folder 257)
  - Bernard & Ella Mazel (Box 6, Folder 258)
  - Gloria Milliken (Box 6, Folder 259)
  - Kristie Miller (Box 6, Folder 260)
  - Stewart Mott (Box 6, Folder 261)
  - Paul Neuthaler (Box 6, Folder 262)
  - Lynda Palevsky (Box 6, Folder 263)
  - Max Palevsky (Box 6, Folder 264)
  - Donald Petrie (Box 6, Folder 265)
  - Isabel Potter (Box 6, Folder 266)
  - Ann Roberts (Box 6, Folder 267)
  - Robert Rubin (Box 6, Folder 268)
  - Alan Sagner (Box 6, Folder 269)
  - Pete Seeger (Box 6, Folder 270)
  - Ira Shapiro (Box 6, Folder 271)
  - Stanley K. Sheinbaum (Box 6, Folder 272a)
  - Francis Smith (Box 6, Folder 272b)
  - Mr. & Mrs. Frank Stanton (Box 6, Folder 273)
  - Cecil Stedman (Box 6, Folder 274)
  - Eve Stern (Box 6, Folder 275)
  - Lee & Byron Stookey (Box 6, Folder 276)
  - George Wallerstein (Box 6, Folder 277)
  - Robert Zevin (Box 6, Folder 278)
- Series VIII: Nonprofit Agencies: 1985-1988
  - Nonprofit Agencies, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 279)
    [Making It Permanent]
  - Nonprofit Agencies, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 280)
  - Nonprofit Agencies: 501(c)(3) and Nonpartisan Voter Registration Legal, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 281)
- Series IX: Nonprofit Agencies: 1995-1996
  - Trainings (Box 6, Folder 282)
  - Women Registering Women (Box 6, Folder 283)
  - Health (Box 6, Folder 284)
  - Implementation Materials (Box 6, Folder 285)
  - Voter Education (Box 6, Folder 286)
  - Voter Education: Get-Out-The-Vote (Box 6, Folder 287)
  - Voter Education Brochure: Spanish (Box 6, Folder 288)
  - 501(c)(3) and Nonpartisan Voter Registration: Legal (Box 6, Folder 289)
  - Launching Meeting (Box 6, Folder 290)
  - Who's Doing What?! (Box 6, Folder 291)
  - Community Service Block Grant (Box 6, Folder 292)
  - Head Start (Box 6, Folder 293)
  - Vote USA, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 294)
  - Vote USA, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 295)
  - Vote USA: Media Caucus (Box 6, Folder 296)
  - Newsletter Articles (Box 6, Folder 297)
  - Child Welfare League of America (Box 7, Folder 298)
  - AIDS Action (Box 7, Folder 299)
  - Planned Parenthood Federation (Box 7, Folder 300)
  - Family Service America (Box 7, Folder 301)
  - Family Resource Coalition (Box 7, Folder 302)
  - National Council of Nonprofit Associations (Box 7, Folder 303)
  - NACCRRA (Box 7, Folder 304)
  - YWCA of the USA (Box 7, Folder 305)
  - National Organizations Various (Box 7, Folder 306)
  - National Organizations Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 307)
  - Internal Memos (Box 7, Folder 308)
  - National Campaign Summary Report (Box 7, Folder 309)
  - National Contacts (Box 7, Folder 310)
  - Mobilization Meeting (Box 7, Folder 311)
  - APHA Conference (Box 7, Folder 312)
  - Anti-Hunger Conference (Box 7, Folder 313)
  - Arts Conference (Box 7, Folder 314)
  - National Association of Public Hospitals (Box 7, Folder 315)
  - LCCR Letter (Box 7, Folder 316)
  - 10 State Update (Box 7, Folder 317)
  - 10 States California (Box 7, Folder 318)
  - 10 States Connecticut (Box 7, Folder 319)
  - 10 States Connecticut Secretary of State (Box 7, Folder 320)
  - 10 States Illinois (Box 7, Folder 321)
  - 10 States Maryland (Box 7, Folder 322)
  - 10 States Massachusetts (Box 7, Folder 323)
  - 10 States New Jersey (Box 7, Folder 324)
  - 10 States Ohio (Box 7, Folder 325)
  - 10 States Pennsylvania (Box 7, Folder 326)
  - Schools Summary Report (Box 7, Folder 327)
  - Schools, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 328)
  - Schools, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 329)
- Series X: National Organizations
  - ACORN, 1984-1994 (Box 7, Folder 330)
  - ACORN, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 331)
  - ACORN, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 332)
  - Advocacy Institute (Box 7, Folder 333)
  - AIDS Action (Box 7, Folder 334)
  - Alliance for Justice (Box 7, Folder 335)
  - American Association of Retired Persons (AARP) (Box 7, Folder 336)
  - American Association of Motor Vehicle Administrators (Box 7, Folder 337)
  - American Association of University Women (Box 7, Folder 338)
  - American Bar Association (Box 7, Folder 339)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 7, Folder 340)
  - The American Coalition of Citizens with Disabilities & The Affiliated Leadership League of and for the Blind of America (Box 7, Folder 341)
  - American Federation of Government Employees (Box 7, Folder 342)
  - Americans for Democratic Action (Box 7, Folder 343)
  - American Forum (Box 7, Folder 344)
  - American Humane (Box 7, Folder 345)
  - American Jewish Congress (Box 7, Folder 346)
  - American Medical Student Association (Box 7, Folder 347)
  - American Orthopsychiatric Association (Box 7, Folder 348)
  - A. Phillip Randolph Institute (Box 7, Folder 349)
  - American Public Health Association, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 350)
  - American Public Health Association, 1987-1996 (Box 8, Folder 351)
  - American Public Power Association (Box 8, Folder 352)
  - American Public Welfare Association, 1983-1993 (Box 8, Folder 353)
  - American Public Welfare Association, February 1994-June 1994 (Box 8, Folder 354)
  - American Public Welfare Association, July 1994-December 1994 (Box 8, Folder 355)
  - American Public Welfare Association, 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 356)
  - Association for the Advancement of Social Work With Groups (Box 8, Folder 357)
  - Association of Neighborhood Housing Developers (Box 8, Folder 358)
  - Association for Retarded Citizens (Box 8, Folder 359)
  - Association of State Democratic Chairs (Box 8, Folder 360)
  - Association for Women in Social Work (Box 8, Folder 361)
  - Ballot Access (Box 8, Folder 362)
  - Bertha Capen Reynolds Society (Box 8, Folder 363)
  - Black Issues Convention (Box 8, Folder 364)
  - Black Leadership Roundtable (Box 8, Folder 365)
  - Blue Mountain Center (Box 8, Folder 366)
  - The Body Shop (Box 8, Folder 367)
  - Business and Professional Women (Box 8, Folder 368)
  - Campaign for Economic Democracy (Box 8, Folder 369)
  - Center for the American Women and Politics (Box 8, Folder 370)
  - Center for Community Change (Box 8, Folder 371)
  - Center for Innovative Diplomacy (Box 8, Folder 372)
  - Center for National Independence in Politics (Box 8, Folder 373)
  - Center for Policy Alternatives 1984 (Box 8, Folder 374)
  - Center for Policy Alternatives, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 375)
  - Center for Policy Alternatives, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 376)
  - Center for Policy Alternatives, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 377)
  - Center for Policy Alternatives, 1988-1990 (Box 8, Folder 378)
  - Center for Policy Alternatives, 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 379)
  - Center for Policy Alternatives, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 380)
  - Center for Policy Alternatives, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 381)
  - Center for Responsive Politics (Box 8, Folder 382)
  - Center for Third World Organization (Box 8, Folder 383)
  - Center on Budget & Policy Priorities (Box 8, Folder 384)
  - Center on Social Welfare & Law (Box 8, Folder 385)
  - Chamber of Commerce (Box 8, Folder 386)
  - Child Care Action Campaign (Box 8, Folder 387)
  - Children's Defense Fund (Box 8, Folder 388)
  - The Children's Foundation (Box 8, Folder 389)
  - Child Welfare League of America (Box 8, Folder 390)
  - Churches Committee for Voter Registration/Education (Box 8, Folder 391)
  - Citizen Action, 1985-July 1987 (Box 8, Folder 392)
  - Citizen Action, August 1987-August 1988 (Box 8, Folder 393)
  - Citizen's Commission (Box 8, Folder 394)
  - Citizen's Commission on Civil Rights (Box 8, Folder 395)
  - Citizenship Education Fund (Box 8, Folder 396)
  - Citizen's Jury (Box 9, Folder 397)
  - Citizen's Leadership (Box 9, Folder 398)
  - Citizens for Participation in Political Action (Box 9, Folder 399)
  - Citizen Participation Project (Box 9, Folder 400)
  - Clearinghouse on Voter Education (Box 9, Folder 401)
  - Coalition on Block Grants and Human Needs (Box 9, Folder 402)
  - Commission for Racial Justice (Box 9, Folder 403)
  - Commission of National Elections (Box 9, Folder 404)
  - Common Cause (Box 9, Folder 405)
  - Community Migrant Health Center (Box 9, Folder 406)
  - Community Service Society (CSS) (Box 9, Folder 407)
  - Communication Workers of American (CWA) (Box 9, Folder 408)
  - [Intentionally eliminated] (Box 9, Folder 409)
  - Connecticut Conference of Municipalities (Box 9, Folder 410)
  - Council of Foundations (Box 9, Folder 411)
  - Council of State Governments (Box 9, Folder 412)
  - Council on Social Work Education (Box 9, Folder 413)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 414)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 415)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1989-1993 (Box 9, Folder 416)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1994-1996 (Box 9, Folder 417)
  - Democratic Socialist of America (Box 9, Folder 418)
  - Disabled American Veterans (Box 9, Folder 419)
  - Disabled But Able To Vote (Box 9, Folder 420)
  - Disabilities Community (Box 9, Folder 421)
  - Election Center, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 422)
  - Election Center, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 423)
  - Election Center, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 424)